We're going to start by looking at the lower bound first.
我们首先来看看下边界
The only way you can get the app to go below one cup of coffee
你可以使得应用达到小于一杯咖啡的唯一方法是
is by pressing the minus button when there is one cup of coffee.
点击—按钮 当只有一杯咖啡的时候
Remember that the minus button triggers the decrement method in the Java file.
记住点击—按钮会触发 Java 文件中的 decrement 方法
So we need to modify the decrement method and
所以我们需要修改 decrement 方法
prevent the app from updating the quantity on the screen.
阻止应用更新屏幕上的 quantity
I open up the code in the Java file for the decrement method.
打开Java 文件中 decrement 方法的代码
Once we're inside this method,
进入这个方法
we don't want this line to be executed if the quantity is already 1.
如果 quantity 已经是1了 我们不想这行代码被执行
Otherwise, this line of code is going to cause a quantity to change to 0.
否则 这行代码将会导致 quantity 为0
I'm going to insert some code at the top of the method.
我将在这个方法的上部插入一些代码
I'll create an if statement,
我加入一个 if 语句
because I only want this logic to be executed if quantity is equal to 1.
因为我希望这个逻辑被执行当 quantity 为1 的时候
Remember in Java that if you want to check if two values are equal to
记住在 Java 中 如果你想检测两个变量是否相等
each other, you need to use the == sign.
你需要使用 “==” 这个符号
The = sign means something else.
“=” 符号有其他的意义
Anyways, going back to the code.
回到代码中
If the quantity is not 1, then we'll just skip this whole block of code and
如果数 quantity 不为1 我们将跳过这个代码块
we'll continue with updating the quantity.
继续更新 quantity
Inside this if statement I'm going to write the return statement.
在这个 if 语句中 我将写入 return 语句
This was the hint that I gave you earlier in the quiz.
在之前的测试中 我给过你这个提示
If the method's return value is void then you can just say return;
如果方法的返回值是空 你可以只写一个 return
with no return value.
后面不用写返回值
This means that we should exit the method immediately without executing
这就意味着我们会退出这个方法 不用执行
the lines of code below it.
下面的代码了
So we skip updating the quantity variable and showing it on screen.
所以我们就会跳过 quantity 变量的更新和显示
If the quantity is not 1, say the quantity is ten,
如果 quantity 不是1 比如 quantity 为 10
then the test condition is false and we skip over this block.
那么测试条件为假 我们就会跳过这段代码
We continue with this lines of code.
继续这行代码
Now, let's look at the case where the upper bound.
让我们来看看上界的情况
The only way to hit 100 is by pressing the plus button when
唯一可以突破100的方法是点击+按钮
there is already 100 cups of coffee.
当有100杯咖啡的时候
The plus button triggers the increment method.
+按钮触发 increment 方法
So we need to modify this method to prevent the app from
所以我们需要修改这个方法来阻止应用
updating the quantity to a 101 cups of coffee.
更新 quantity 到101 杯咖啡
Within the increment method we add some additional logic like we did for
在 increment 方法中加入一些附加的逻辑 就像我们在
the decrement method.
decrement 方法中做的一样
If the quantity variable is currently at a 100
如果 quantity 变量的当前值是100
then we should exit the method early.
那么我们将提早退出这个方法
Otherwise we should continue by incrementing the quantity by
否则 quantity 就会继续增加
one more cup of coffee and then displaying it on the screen.
并且显示在屏幕上
Let's run this on our device to see what happens.
在设备上运行应用 看看会发生什么
Okay, if I hit the minus button a bunch of times,
好的 如果我多次点击—按钮
then it just stops at 1 cup of coffee.
那么它就会停在1杯咖啡的时候
In order to test that the upper bound works, I'm going to change the initial
为了检测上界是否正常 我将在
quantity variable in our Java file to be 99 cups of coffee.
Java 文件中把 quantity 变量的初始值修改为99杯咖啡
I'm going to make a similar change in the layout as well.
在布局文件中也做类似的修改
Nine cups of coffee is $195.
9杯咖啡花费195美元
Now I'm going to run it on the device.
在设备上运行它
If I hit the plus button a bunch of times,
如果我多次点击+按钮
you can see that it stays at 100 cups of coffee.
你可以看见它只显示100杯咖啡
Nice!
漂亮！
Our code works.
代码运行正常
If you chose to do the challenge problem, here's the solution code.
如果你选择做一些挑战性的问题 这是解决方法的代码
Within the increment method, if the quantity is already at 100 cups of
在 increment 方法中 如果 quantity 已经是 100杯咖啡了
coffee, then we show this toast message before we exit the method early.
在我们退出这个方法之前显示这个 Toast 消息
To create a toast message, you call Toast.makeText and
为了创建 Toast 消息 我们调用 Toast.makeText 方法
you pass in three different input arguments.
并且输入3个不同的参数
You pass in a context, which is this activity, you pass it a message,
输入 context 它指向这个 activity 在这个情况下输入一个消息
which is you cannot have more than 100 coffees in this case.
不能点超过 100 杯咖啡
And we also specify how long it should show up on screen.
我们也指定它在屏幕上显示的时间
We're just saying the toast message should show for a short amount of time.
我们设置这个 Toast 消息持续较短的时间
All this code creates a single toast object, and
所有的这些代码创建了一个 Toast 对象
then we call a method show on that object.
然后我们在这个对象上调用方法
Similarly within the decrement method, if the quantity is already at 1 cup of
与 decrement 方法类似 如果 quantity 已经是1杯咖啡了
coffee then we show and error message right before we exit the method early.
那么在我们退出这个方法之前就显示一个错误提示信息
Again, this statement creates a toast object with this message and
再说一遍 这个语句创建了一个有该消息的 Toast 对象
then we call the method show on it.
然后我们可以调用它的方法
By the way, we use this site to help us figure out how to display a toast
顺便说一句 我们用这个网站来帮助我们学习如何
message in our app.
在应用中显示 Toast消息
Here's some sample code that you could have used.
这是一些示例代码 你可以使用它们
In general, it's a good idea to let the user know what's happening,
一般来说 通过用户界面上的错误信息或者其他的提示信息来
with an error message or some other indication in the user interface.
告知用户发生了什么 是非常好的想法
Otherwise, they might think that the app is broken and
否则 他们可能会认为应用崩溃了
not responding to their button clicks.
因为应用没有对他们点击按钮做出响应